<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">KnowBible</string>
    <string name="deleting">Delete all verses?</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="my_daily_verse">Мой стих дня:</string>

    <string name="title_articles">Articles</string>
    <string name="title_bible">Bible</string>
    <string name="title_more">More</string>

    <!-- TextView -->
    <string name="tv_find_your_daily_verse">Find your daily verse!</string>
    <string name="tv_find_verse">Verse</string>
    <string name="tv_list">List</string>
    <string name="tv_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="tv_remember_verse">Запомнить \\n стих</string>
    <string name="tv_interface_language">Interface language</string>
    <string name="tv_theme">Theme</string>
    <string name="tv_have_to_download_bible">In order to use the application, you need to download at least one of the Bible translations presented. After the translation has loaded, click on it and you will be taken to the Bible window.</string>
    <string name="tv_new_article">New article!</string>
    <string name="tv_about_writing_articles">We are happy to give you the opportunity to write and publish your own articles! To do this, you need to contact us by clicking on the link below to our Telegram channel or to our Instagram page. If your article passes the test for compliance with the rules set by us, we will publish it. You can familiarize yourself with the regulations by clicking on the button below.</string>
    <string name="tv_notes">Notes</string>
    <string name="tv_search">Search</string>
    <string name="ed_search">Search…</string>
    <string name="tv_daily_verse">Daily verse</string>
    <string name="tv_bible_translation">Bible translation</string>
    <string name="tv_downloading_canceled">Translation downloading aborted</string>
    <string name="tv_copy_verse">Copy</string>
    <string name="tv_highlight_verse">Highlight</string>
    <string name="tv_add_note">Add note</string>
    <string name="tv_share">Share</string>
    <string name="tv_color_sample">«For God so loved the world…»</string>
    <string name="tv_remove_highlighted_verse">Remove highlighting</string>
    <string name="tv_select_color">Select color</string>
    <string name="tv_add_to_daily_verse">Add to «Daily verse»</string>
    <string name="tv_remove_from_daily_verse">Remove from «Daily Verse»</string>

    <!-- Button -->
    <string name="btn_old_testament">Old\nTestament</string>
    <string name="btn_new_testament">New\nTestament</string>
    <string name="btn_download">Download</string>
    <string name="btn_old_testament_short">O.T.</string>
    <string name="btn_new_testament_short">N.T.</string>
    <string name="btn_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="btn_select">Select</string>
    <string name="btn_save_note">Save</string>
    <string name="btn_apply">Apply</string>

    <!-- CheckBox -->
    <string name="cb_add_bold_text">Add Bold</string>
    <string name="cb_add_underline">Add underline</string>

    <!-- Toast -->
    <string name="toast_find_verse">Find your Daily Verse</string>
    <string name="toast_share_verse">Share verse</string>
    <string name="toast_translation_saved">Translate saved</string>
    <string name="toast_download_translation">Download the translation before using it.</string>
    <string name="toast_no_internet_connection">No internet connection</string>
    <string name="toast_select_translation">Select translation</string>
    <string name="toast_please_wait">Please wait while the translation download is completed</string>
    <string name="toast_error_picture_loading">Picture loading failed</string>
    <string name="toast_note_added">Note added</string>
    <string name="toast_note_edited">Note edited</string>
    <string name="toast_note_deleted">Note deleted</string>
    <string name="toast_field_cant_be_empty">Field cannot be empty</string>

    <string name="et_thoughts">Your thoughts</string>

    <string name="folder_name">KnowBible</string>
    <string name="russian_language_translation">Russian</string>
    <string name="ukrainian_language_translation">Ukrainian</string>
    <string name="english_language_translation">English</string>
    <string name="syno_translation">Synodal Translation</string>
    <string name="ubio_translation">Ivan Ogienko Translation</string>
    <string name="umt_translation">Ukrainian Modern Translation</string>
    <string name="kjv_translation">King James Translation</string>
    <string name="asv_translation">American Standard Version</string>
    <string name="english_lang">English</string>
    <string name="english_lang_local_name">English</string>
    <string name="russian_lang">Русский</string>
    <string name="russian_lang_local_name">Russian</string>
    <string name="ukrainian_lang">Українська</string>
    <string name="ukrainian_lang_local_name">Ukrainian</string>
    <string name="nrt_translation">New Russian Translation</string>
    <string name="day_theme">Light theme</string>
    <string name="night_theme">Dark theme</string>
    <string name="book_theme">Book theme</string>
    <string name="telegram_channel_link">https://bit.ly/3rXomNt</string>
    <string name="instagram_channel_link">https://bit.ly/2TPOblY</string>
    <string name="know_bible_help_mail">knowbiblehelp@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="donation_link">https://secure.wayforpay.com/payment/know_bible_donate</string>
    <string name="verse_copied">Verse copied</string>
    <string name="toast_no_verses_in_daily_verse">You have not added a single verse in «DailyVerse»</string>
    <string name="tv_empty_daily_verses_list">List of verses is empty</string>
    <string name="rb_all_bible">All Bible</string>
    <string name="rb_old_testament">Old Testament</string>
    <string name="rb_new_testament">New Testament</string>
    <string name="toast_at_least_three_letters">The search field must contain at least three letters</string>
    <string name="btn_home">Home</string>
    <string name="btn_interpretation">Interpretation</string>
    <string name="tab_first_interpretation">Interpretation by Dallas Seminary</string>
    <string name="tab_second_interpretation">Interpretation by William MacDonald</string>
    <string name="tab_third_interpretation">Interpretation by Matthew Henry</string>
    <string name="tv_support">SUPPORT</string>

    <string name="old_testament_info"><![CDATA[<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>&bull; Short description</strong>: The Old Testament is the first part of the Holy Scriptures, of the Bible. When we talk about the essence of the name, then we are talking about a number of covenants or agreements that the Lord entered into with people (the covenant between God and Noah, between God and Abraham, between God and His people Israel, as well as between God and David), but which were terminated by the people of Israel because of their unfaithfulness. In this regard, God, speaking through his prophets, indicated that He will conclude a new covenant with people, which will renew the very agreement between God and people. Since the New Testament came with the coming of Jesus Christ, the previous Testament was called Old in the Bible.</p> <p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Old Testament was written for over a dozen centuries, from the 15th century BC to about the 4th century BC.</p> <p class=\"MsoNormal\" style=\"margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: left;\"><strong>&bull; Authorship</strong>: The Old Testament consists of 39 separate books written in different genres and styles, on which more than 30 authors from a wide range of population worked, almost never knowing each other: kings, leaders, military leaders, shepherds and many others. But the person who always controlled the entire process of writing and opened his eyes to the main problems and topics covered in the books was the Lord God.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="new_testament_info"><![CDATA[<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>&bull; Short Description</strong>: The New Testament is the second part of the Holy Scripture, the Bible. The essence of the name lies in the event that marked the beginning of the New Testament, a new agreement between God and man, namely in the coming of the Lord Jesus Christ, the Savior of people. An unconditionally loving God, incarnate in man and redeeming sinful people from eternal death, paved the way for humanity to have a direct relationship with Him. In almost every written address states only condition that a person must comply with in order to become a participant in a new agreement between God and man - this is faith in the Lord Jesus Christ as his personal Savior from sins and eternal death.</p> <p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The New Testament was written for about 50 years - from half of the 1st century AD. and until the end of the 1st century after AD.</p> <p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>&bull; Authorship</strong>: The New Testament consists of 27 books and epistles, most of which were written by the apostles - disciples of Christ. But as in the Old Testament, in the New Testament, the Lord God was the person who always controlled the entire process of writing and opened his eyes to the main problems and topics covered in the books.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="tv_highlighted_verses">Highlighted verses</string>
    <string name="tv_donation_text">We need your support so that our ministry is able to exist and grow!</string>
    <string name="tv_in_development">IN DEVELOPMENT</string>
    <string name="toast_share_note">Share note</string>
    <string name="btn_ok">OK</string>
    <string name="tv_contact_us">Contact us</string>
    <string name="Details">Details</string>
    <string name="tv_donate_details"><![CDATA[<p style=\"text-align: left;\">You give to:</p> <p style=\"text-align: left;\">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&bull;&nbsp; &nbsp;financial support of developers (currently a married couple)<br />&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&bull;&nbsp; &nbsp;development of current and creation of new projects for the preaching of the Gospel</p> <p style=\"text-align: left;\">For more information you can contact us in the section \"Contact us\"</p> <p>May the Lord God bless you!</p>]]></string>
    <string name="tv_articles_regulations"><![CDATA[<p style=\"text-align: center;\"><strong>Regulations for writing articles</strong></p> <p>This regulation exists in order to streamline the process of writing, editing and publishing articles. Below is a list of requirements:</p> <p>1. The volume of the article is from 300 to 700 words. Such a small volume is due to our desire to preserve the capacity, conciseness and dynamics of the text.<br />2. The article must be sent to us as a Word document.<br />3. At the end of the article, be sure to indicate the name of the author and a list of references (that is, the sources from which you took information for writing the article), if any.<br />4. If you have the ability to translate a text, then provide us with an article translated into all necessary languages ​​(at the moment it is Russian, English and Ukrainian), thereby you will help speed up the process of editing and publishing your article. If the translation process is an overwhelming task for you, then we will take care of the translation of the article ourselves, but in this case, the process of editing and publishing your article will be somewhat delayed.<br />5. Since our application is directly Biblical, articles should be based only on the texts of the Holy Scriptures and / or on your personal testimonies, which, again, are based on the Word of God.<br />6. The KnowBible app is designed to help all Christians, regardless of denomination, read and study the Bible. But, based on the above paragraph 5, your article cannot contain doctrines that contradict the confirmed Biblical truths (for example, Jesus Christ is God, the Trinity of God, Jesus Christ is the only personal Savior of each person).<br />7. The speech style of your article should not be colloquial. The text should be written in compliance with spelling and punctuation rules.<br />8. If the content of the article does not comply with the requirements of this regulation, we reserve the right to refuse you to publish the article.<br />9. For all questions, please contact us at any time in the section \"Contact us\"</p> <p>May the Lord God bless you!</p> <p style=\"text-align: left;\">&nbsp;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p>]]></string>

    <!-- Bible books description -->
    <string name="book_description_10"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Genesis (literally from Hebrew \"In the beginning\")</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Moses, prophet</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Approximately 15th century BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The book describes the creation of the world by God and the fall of people, due to which sin entered the world, bringing death, evil and trouble. The central character in Genesis is a man named Abraham. God chooses Abraham to be the father of the great nation of Israel and promises that through him all the nations of the earth will be blessed. The icon depicts one star representing Israel and standing out from the others, just as God chose Abraham to create a unique people. The other stars, of course, are twelve, which echoes the twelve tribes of Israel.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_20"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Exodus (from Hebrew \"Elle-Shemot\" - \"The Book of Names\", but received the name from the Septuagint), the second book of Moses</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Prophet Moses.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Approximately 1446 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The book of Exodus tells the story of the departure of the Jewish people from Egypt: from the beginning of the oppression of Jacob\'s descendants to the construction and consecration of a marching temple - the Tabernacle. Upon arriving at Sinai, God gives the people the Law on two stone tablets.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_30"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Leviticus (literally \"And the Lord called\" from Hebrew, but got its name from the Greek \"Leutikon\").</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Prophet Moses.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: About the second half of the 15th century BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Only a small part of the book is narrative in nature. The book of Leviticus has almost exclusively legislative content, it is devoted to the religious and cult side of the life of the people of Israel, especially the system of sacrifices. Leviticus lays down laws on sacrifices, priestly duties, and other aspects of the law. The main idea of the book comes down to one line from God: \"And ye shall be holy unto me: for I the LORD am holy, and have severed you from other people, that ye should be mine\" (Lev. 20:26). &ldquo;Holy&rdquo; means &ldquo;separated,&rdquo; and the icon indicates that Israel is called and created to be different from the rest of the world.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_40"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Numbers (the title was derived from the Septuagint - Greek. \"Arithmoi\" - numbers; from Hebrew in the original it sounds \"In the desert\").</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Prophet Moses.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: about 1406 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: the book tells about how God disciplined the Israelite people before entering the promised land. It is here that the Israelites have roamed the desert for 40 years. The book also provides detailed data on the calculation of the people, its individual tribes, firstborn, etc.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_50"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Deuteronomy (translation from the Septuagint &ndash; &laquo;deuteronomio&raquo; - the second law; the Hebrew title of the book sounds like \"these are the essence of the word\" - according to the first words at the beginning of the book).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Prophet Moses.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Approximately 14th century BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The book has the character of a farewell speech, the last sermon of Moses, addressed to the Jewish people. Deuteronomy literally means \"the second present\", meaning the repetition of the Law of Moses. Deuteronomy is, in a sense, the ancient constitution of Israel. Moses sets out the law, repeats the 10 commandments again, and specifically addresses how they should be applied in the promised land.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_60"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Joshua (from Hebrew Yehoshua).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The main body of the book was written by Joshua, except for the events described after his death.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: approximately 1406 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Joshua is the story of Israel\'s seizure of the promised land.&nbsp; The first half of the book is full of battles, including the famous battle in a town called Jericho, whose \"walls collapsed\" at the sound of a trumpet.&nbsp; The second half of the book is devoted to the division of the earth, which is not as interesting as, say, the stationary sun (Josh. 10:13).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_70"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Judges (from Hebrew \"shopetim\" - \"judges\").</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely the author was Samuel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Between 1040 and 1020 BC.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The judges show us the downward moral spiral that occurs after the death of Joshua.&nbsp; The book is disheartening, but it shows us why Israel needs a godly king (Judges 21:25).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_80"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Ruth (or from Hebrew \"Scroll of Ruth\").</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely the author was Samuel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: approximately the second half of the 12th century BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Ruth is a story of hope and redemption. Ruth, the widow, faithfully helps her mother-in-law collect grain, which attracts the attention of a wealthy farmer named Boaz…</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_90"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: First Book of Samuel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: It is assumed that the book was started by the prophet Samuel (first 24 chapters), and after his death it was continued by the prophets Nathan and Gad.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The only thing that can be said for certain about the date of writing of 1 Kings (Samuel) and 2 Kings (Samuel) is that they were written between 931 and 722 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Book of Samuel is the story of David becoming king of Israel. God makes a special promise to David: there will always be a descendant of David on the throne.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p>Note: First and second books of Samuel were originally one book, so they got one icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_100"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Second Book of Samuel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: It is assumed that the book was started by the prophet Samuel (first 24 chapters), and after his death it was continued by the prophets Nathan and Gad.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The only thing that can be said for certain about the date of writing of 1 Kings (Samuel) and 2 Kings (Samuel) is that they were written between 931 and 722 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Book of Samuel is the story of David becoming king of Israel. God makes a special promise to David: there will always be a descendant of David on the throne.</p> <p>Note: First and second books of Samuel were originally one book, so they got one icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_110"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: First Book of Kings</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: most likely one of these people: either Ezra, or Ezekiel, or Jeremiah</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Between 560 and 538 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: First and second books of kingdoms tell the story of the kings of Israel. The nation is divided into two kingdoms (North and South) and this story examines whether the nation is true to the Law of Moses.&nbsp; Almost all kings show complete opposition to the Law of Moses, so the books of kingdoms end with both kingdoms being captured by other empires.</p> <p>Note: First and second Books of Kings were originally the same book, so they have the same icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_120"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Second Book of Kings</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: most likely one of these people: either Ezra, or Ezekiel, or Jeremiah</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Between 560 and 538 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: First and second books of kingdoms tell the story of the kings of Israel. The nation is divided into two kingdoms (North and South) and this story examines whether the nation is true to the Law of Moses.&nbsp; Almost all kings show complete opposition to the Law of Moses, so the books of kingdoms end with both kingdoms being captured by other empires.</p> <p>Note: First and second Books of Kings were originally the same book, so they have the same icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_130"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: First Book of Chronicles (from Hebrew \"Acts of the Days\")</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely the author of the first and second Chronicles was Ezra</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Around 400 BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: First and second Chronicles give a great overview of the history of ancient Israel, with an emphasis on the covenant God made with David. The book originates from the very origins of the human race, the first word of the book is Adam. Due to the fact that this entire huge period of time was described (with a colossal amount of genealogy), Chronicles receive an hourglass.</p> <p>Note: First and second Chronicles were originally one book, so they received one icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_140"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Second Book of Chronicles (from Hebrew \"Acts of the Days\")</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely the author of the first and second Chronicles was Ezra</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Around 400 BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: First and second Chronicles give a great overview of the history of ancient Israel, with an emphasis on the covenant God made with David. The book originates from the very origins of the human race, the first word of the book is Adam. Due to the fact that this entire huge period of time was described (with a colossal amount of genealogy), Chronicles receive an hourglass.</p> <p>Note: First and second Chronicles were originally one book, so they received one icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_150"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Book of Ezra</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely the author was Ezra. Jewish traditions testify to this, and also the texts in 7:27 – 9:15 speak in favor of this, where the author speaks of himself in the first person.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Around 450 BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: When the Jews return from Babylon, they are ordered to rebuild the temple of God in Jerusalem. Ezra tells us how it happened and what obstacles stood in his way.</p> <p>Note: For a time the books of Ezra and Nehemiah were treated as one, but the books look different enough to be limited to the same icons.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_160"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Book of Nehemiah</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most researchers claim Nehemiah was the author</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written in Jerusalem and covers the history from the circumstances of Nehemiah\'s arrival in Jerusalem from Persia (445 BC) to his second arrival in Jerusalem after traveling to the court of the Persian king (432 BC). It was around this time that the book was written.</p> <p>&bull; Summary: Nehemiah rallies the Jews together to rebuild the walls of Jerusalem and remember their covenant with God. This is Nehemiah&rsquo;s story, mostly in his own words.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_190"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Book of Esther. Most likely the name Esther comes from the Babylonian goddess of love Ishtar.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author could have been either Mordecai, or Ezra, or Nehemiah, or some Persian Jew who returned to Israel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Between 450 BC and 331 BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Esther is the story of how a Jewish woman becomes queen of Persia&mdash;just in time to stop a nefarious plot to kill off the Jews throughout the empire.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_220"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Job.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: One can only speculate about the author of this book. It could have been Job himself or Elihu (Job\'s fourth friend). Jewish tradition attributes this book to Moses. Also some consider Solomon to be the author of this book, since he loved poetry and was himself a poet, and because of some similarities between the book of Job and the book of Proverbs.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The date of writing is unknown. But, if we consider Job to be the author of the book (most likely Job lived during the time of the patriarchs), then the approximate date is from 2100 to 1900 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Book of Job is called unmatched in world literature. In its content, it reaches the heights of religious thought and in its form it belongs to the best examples of poetry. Job is a man who was doing well until Satan began trying to force Job to curse God. Job loses his family, wealth and good health. Most of the book is devoted to Job and his friends trying to understand why these terrible things are happening to him.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_230"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: English name &laquo;Psalter&raquo; is of Greek origin: the word &laquo;psalmos&raquo; translates the Hebrew &laquo;mitzmor&raquo;, which meant playing a string instrument.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The Psalter is a collection of songs and hymns, it was authored by several people: David, Asaph, Heman, Ethan, Solomon and Moses. King David is considered to be the author of 73 Psalms.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The time when the Psalms were written covers the period from Moses to the return of the Jews who were taken away from it to the promised land.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Book of the Psalter is a collection of lyric poetry about God and faith; here are collected many edifying, inspirational and solemn hymns.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_240"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Bool Title</strong>: Book of Proverbs of Solomon. The book is named after the Israelite king Solomon.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The book consists of eight sections that have arisen at different times, with the participation of several authors (sages). The author of most of the book was King Solomon. He edited some sections, recording the parables of various sages. Sections VI and VII belong to a certain Agur and King Lemuel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book of Proverbs took its final form during the time of King Hezekiah, 300 years after Solomon. The final date of its appearance is considered approximately 700 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Book of Proverbs is a book of moral and ethical instruction that touches on many aspects of human life. The instructions contained in it teach readers how to live piously and wisely, how to avoid on their way the traps that people set for themselves and each other because of unreasonable and displeasing behavior to God.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_250"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Ecclesiastes. Literally translated from the Hebrew word &laquo;Ecclesiastes&raquo; means &laquo;Preacher&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely, the author was Solomon, king of Israel and son of David.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Solomon probably wrote in the last years of his life, no later than 931 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Book of Ecclesiastes is a poetic and philosophical reflection. The main question of the book is: \"What is the point?\" Ecclesiastes often uses the phrase \"under the sun\" to indicate that the author is observing how the world works without regard for divine intervention. Solomon mainly warns young people, not excluding others, from following the earthly path in the footsteps of human wisdom and exhorted them to live according to the revelation of God\'s wisdom.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_260"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Song of Solomon. The title means that this song is the best of all 1005 pieces of music by Solomon (1 Kings 4:32).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely, the author was Solomon, king of Israel and son of David.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was probably written between 971 and 931. BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Song of Solomon is an epic love poem. At the same time, it is important to consider it as a whole poetic work, as a book of wisdom, and not as a series of love poems without a common theme and author.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_290"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Book of Isaiah. Isaiah\'s name means &laquo;The Lord is salvation&raquo;. In the New Testament this book is quoted more than all the Old Testament books, more than 65 times. And the name of Isaiah is mentioned in the New Testament more than 20 times.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Isaiah himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written about 681 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Isaiah witnesses a brilliant manifestation of God on the throne in chapter 6. In this vision, Isaiah cries out to God: &laquo;Here I am! Send me! &raquo;. God does send Isaiah &mdash; with a message of judgment and ultimately consolation for Israel.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_300"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Jeremiah. The name Jeremiah means &laquo;Jehovah affirms&raquo; (in the sense of laying the foundation).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Jeremiah himself. But in writing the text he was helped by the scribe Baruch.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written about 561 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Jeremiah is known as the &laquo;weeping prophet&raquo;. Prophets were not popular in their day, but Jeremiah\'s difficulties deserve special attention. He is imprisoned, threatened with death, besieged and dragged from country to country. He preaches the word of God, but people do not listen.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_310"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: In Hebrew, the book is given the title <em>ekah</em> (&laquo;how&raquo;, which expresses horror) used in 1:1, 2:1 and 4:1. However, the rabbis soon began to call the book Loud Wailing or Lamentation.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely, the author was the prophet Jeremiah himself. Perhaps the scribe Baruch also helped in writing.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was most likely written during or shortly after the fall of Jerusalem in 586 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Jerusalem has fallen! This small collection of intricate verses is filled with sorrow over the destruction of Jerusalem. Jeremiah cries out to God in the hope of restoration. This is the only book in the entire Old Testament that contains only mournful laments, and which is a song of mourning for the once beautiful city. The book commemorates the fall of Jerusalem and teaches all believers how to endure suffering.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_330"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Book of Ezekiel. The name Ezekiel means &laquo;Strengthened by God&raquo;. This is what he was in carrying out the prophetic ministry to which God had called Him (3:8–9).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Ezekiel himself. He was a contemporary of the prophet Jeremiah and the prophet Daniel (who was the same age as him).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The last dated statement of Ezekiel is from 571–570. BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: God appoints Ezekiel to be the &laquo;guardian&raquo; of his people &mdash; someone to warn the people of what is coming. At the beginning of the book, Ezekiel sees the glory of God leave Jerusalem. Jerusalem remains vulnerable to future violence. But at the end of the book, Ezekiel sees the restoration of Israel and the return of God\'s glory. In Exodus, the tabernacle was filled with the glory of God, which took the form of a cloud. When creating the icon, the same images were used.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_340"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Daniel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Daniel himself. Thanks to the royal appointment, he quickly reached the position of statesman and was a confidant of the kings, as well as a prophet in two world empires - Babylonian and Medo-Persian. Christ spoke of Daniel as the author of this book.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written between 536 and 530. BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Daniel was God\'s spokesman for Gentiles and Jews, proclaiming God\'s purpose for the present and future. He interprets dreams, sees visions, and focuses on God\'s sovereignty over the world\'s empires.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_350"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Hosea. His name means the same as the name Jesus &ndash; &laquo;salvation&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Hosea himself. His book is the only source of information about him. He was a native of the Northern Kingdom of Israel. Hosea continued the preaching of Amos in the north and was a contemporary of Isaiah and Micah, who prophesied in Judea.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written about 750 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Hosea marries a harlot who leaves him. Then God tells Hosea to marry her again. This is a metaphor for how God remains faithful to the Northern Kingdom even when the people are not faithful to Him.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_360"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Joel. The name Joel means &laquo;The Lord is God&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Joel himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written between 639 and 608. BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Joel explains that the recent plague of locusts is a punishment from God and calls Judas to repentance.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_370"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Amos. The name &laquo;Amos&raquo; means &laquo;burden&raquo; or &laquo;burden bearer&raquo;. It should not be confused with another Amos (Heb. Amoz), the father of Isaiah, whose name means &laquo;strong&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was Amos himself. He was a contemporary of Jonah, Hosea, and Isaiah.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written about 750 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The prophet Amos has no family history of prophetic ministry. Amos says: &laquo;I was no prophet, neither was I a prophet\'s son; but I was an herdman, and a gatherer of sycomore fruit&raquo; (Amos 7:14).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_380"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Obadiah. The name means &laquo;Servant of the Lord&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Most likely, the author was Obadiah himself, but little is known about him. Obadiah was probably a contemporary of Elijah and Elisha.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written between 850 and 780 AD. BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: God vows to overthrow the hilltop people of Edom and one day rebuild Jerusalem on Mount Zion.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_390"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Jonah. Jonah\'s name means &laquo;dove&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: There is no definitive indication of Jonah\'s authorship in the book. Added to doubts is the fact that the book is being written in a third person. On the other hand, in the Old Testament, the authors already used this way of writing (Ex. 11:3, 1 Sam. 12:11). Moreover, the described details of what is happening in the sea could have been presented, most likely, only by a participant in the events, namely, by the prophet Jonah.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written around 760 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The story of a man who foolishly tried to run away from God. The Lord led him through a number of amazing circumstances, revealing Himself as, on the one hand, a just God, and, on the other hand, a merciful God, who hears someone calling to Him even from the depths of the sea and being in the belly of a huge fish.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_400"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book Title</strong>: Book of Micah. The name Micah is a short form of the name meaning \"Who is like the Lord.\"</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Micah himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written around 720 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Micah calls out for justice in the land, and it&rsquo;s in this book that we find those three little lines we could all stand to follow more closely (Mic. 6:8):</p> <p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; - Act justly&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; - Love mercy</p> <p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; - Walk humbly with God&nbsp;</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_410"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Naum. The name Nahum means &laquo;approval, consolation&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Nahum himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written between 695 and 642. BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: God is about to bring a world of pain to Nineveh as punishment for her sins.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_420"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Habakkuk. The name Habakkuk means most likely &laquo;embracing&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Habakkuk himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written around 610 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Prophet Habakkuk cries out to God: &laquo;How long will you allow the people to avoid punishment for injustice?&raquo; This sparks a controversy between God and Habakkuk, culminating in a song to worship the Lord.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_430"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Zephaniah. The name Zephaniah means &laquo;the Lord hides&raquo;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Zephaniah himself. He was a contemporary of the prophet Jeremiah</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written about 625 BC.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: God wants to remove everything and restore everything: Israel, Judah and the surrounding nations. When everyone is justly judged, then everything will be much better.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_440"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Book of Haggai. The name Haggai means &laquo;Festive&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Haggai himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written around 520 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Jews postponed the restoration of the temple, but built themselves beautiful houses. Prophet Haggai calls people to complete the construction of the temple and again enjoy God\'s blessings.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_450"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: The Book of Zechariah. The name Zechariah means &laquo;The Lord remembers&raquo;.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Zechariah himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written around 500 BC.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Zechariah has more visions than any other minor prophet. Key recurring phrase in the book: &laquo;I looked up …&raquo;. The icon should help avoid confusion between Zechariah and Zephaniah.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_460"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Book of Malachi.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was the prophet Malachi himself.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written between 440 and 400 BC</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: God love His people, but they abandoned Him. Therefore, God is sending Malachi some messages. The book is full of hypothetical dialogues that go something like this:</p> <p>God: &laquo;I loved you&raquo;.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p>Israel: &laquo;How Did You Love Us?&raquo;.</p> <p>This back and forth motion is echoed in the book, so it is also present in the icon.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_470"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: The Gospel of Matthew. The name Matthew means \"Gift of God\"</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was Matthew, who was a tax collector before meeting Christ.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The gospel was written between AD 50 and 55 AD</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Gospel of Matthew tells us the good news of Jesus Christ, the true King of the Jews.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_480"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: The Gospel of Mark.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was Mark. He was a close friend of the apostle Peter, and a person periodically referred to in the book of Acts as &laquo;John called Mark&raquo; (Acts 12:12, 25; 15:37, 39).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The gospel was written approximately 60 AD.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Gospel of Mark is a dynamic and relevant story about Jesus, the servant of man and the Son of God. This gospel often uses the word &laquo;straightway&raquo;, and it is the shortest gospel in the Bible.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_490"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: The Gospel of Luke.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was Luke. Based on the information presented in the New Testament, it can be said quite unequivocally that he was a friend of the Apostle Paul and a doctor.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The Gospel was written around 61 AD.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Luke interviewed eyewitnesses to compile a biography of Jesus Christ, listing all events in chronological order (Luke 1:1–3).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_500"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: The Gospel of John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author was John, son of Zebedee and one of Christ\'s three closest disciples (along with James and Peter).</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The Gospel was written about 90 A.D.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: John writes his gospel in the form of a series of signs so that the reader can believe in Christ and find life in Him (John 20: 30&ndash;31).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_510"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Acts of the Holy Apostles</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author of the book is the same Luke, who was mentioned in the description of his Gospel.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The book was written approximately AD 61 or AD 62.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Acts tells about the descent of the Holy Spirit and the spread of the Gospel throughout the world. The Holy Spirit appears in the form of tongues of fire (Acts 2: 3–4), which this icon reflects. This book is, relatively speaking, the second part of Luke\'s story about Christ and His ministry (the first part is the Gospel of Luke, respectively), which continued in His disciples, and then throughout the world.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_520"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Romans.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about 58 A.D.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Romans shows us how the gospel works: moving from a life without Christ to a life with Him, a life in constant competition between the flesh and God\'s nature, and much more. The gears represent Paul\'s explanation of the mechanics of the gospel.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_530"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 1-st Epistle to Corinthians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 54 &ndash; 55.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The Church in Corinth is divided over various issues: spiritual leaders, legal issues, diet, and more. Paul writes that they focus on glorifying God rather than fighting one another.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_540"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 2-nd Epistle to Corinthians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 56 &ndash; 57.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: There was disagreement and division between Paul and the Corinthians. Paul writes a letter to achieve reconciliation.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_550"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Galatians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 49.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The churches in Galatia embraced the idea that Christians should live according to the ceremonial Law of Moses, which is contrary to the gospel preached by Paul. Paul draws the attention of the Galatians to how they should receive the Law.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_560"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Ephesians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 62.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul encourages Ephesians to &laquo;walk worthy of a calling&raquo; (Ephesians 4:1), that is, he encourages them to follow Christ.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_570"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Philippians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 61–62.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul, while in prison, writes to the Philippians to rejoice no matter what.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_580"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Colossians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 61–62.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul is writing this letter to establish faith in Christ in the young church. He encourages them to think about things above, because they were raised with Christ (Col. 3:1–2).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_590"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 1–st Epistle to Thessalonians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 51–52.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul heard of the many good works of the Church of Thessalonica, and he rejoices in this and encourages them to &laquo;abound more and more&raquo; (1 Thess. 4:1).</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_600"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 2–nd Epistle to Thessalonians.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 51–52.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul writes again to the Thessalonians instructing them how to live in the light of the coming of the Lord.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_610"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 1-st Epistle to Timothy.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 63 &ndash; 65.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: This is a letter from one shepherd to another on how to lead his church.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_620"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 2-nd Epistle to Timothy.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 66 &ndash; 67.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul is close to death and says goodbye to Timothy heartily. It is here that Paul hands over the torch of the gospel ministry and encourages Timothy to also pass it on in his day.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_630"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Titus.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 62 &ndash; 64.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: The main purpose of the message is to prepare the churches of Crete for effective evangelism ministry. This letter gives Titus some directions on how to do this.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_640"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Philemon.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Paul.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about A.D. 63.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Paul sends a letter and an escaped slave to his friend Philemon. Philemon is the master of a slave, but Paul advises Philemon to take him back as a brother, not as a slave.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_650"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: Epistle to Hebrews.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author of Hebrews is unknown. Theologians suggest that the author could have been Paul, Barnabas, Silas, Apollos, Luke, Philip, Priscilla, Aquila, or Clement of Rome. In any case, our main concern is not who wrote this message, but what this message about. Ultimately, the Holy Spirit is the author of any text in the Bible.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 63 &ndash; 64.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Hebrews shows that Jesus Christ is more than anything in the Old Testament &mdash; more than any hero, covenant, priest, sacrifice or angel.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_660"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: The Epistle of James.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author of the letter was James, the brother of Christ.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about A.D. 45. Most likely, this is the first book of the New Testament.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: In this letter, James encourages Christians to continue to do good works that would validate their faith in Christ.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_670"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Boot title</strong>: 1-st Epistle of Peter.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Peter.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 64 &ndash; 65.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Peter speaks of Christians having to suffer, but that this will result in a glorious future for them.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_680"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: 2-nd Epistle of Peter.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle Peter.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 67 &ndash; 68.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Peter is about to die, so he writes a quick reminder to Christians. He focuses on the sincere faith and teaching of the apostles and warns that false teachers will appear. A note is drawn on the icon depicted as a prototype of memorizing something laconic and important.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_690"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: 1–st Epistle of John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written around 90–95. N. E.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: This letter is a kind of continuation of the Gospel of John. The Epistle, relatively speaking, describes the ways of identifying the true children of God. Also, this message contains many truths about love. The book is dedicated to knowledge and love.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_700"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: 2-nd Epistle of John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle John.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about 90 &ndash; 95 A.D.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: This is a message about walking in love.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_710"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: 3-rd Epistle of John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about 90 &ndash; 95 A.D.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: This book talks about truth, love, and fellowship, especially hospitality. John writes to a guy named Gaius, telling him to continue to show hospitality to the saints. Although one of the leaders of the local church condemns this behavior.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_720"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Epistle of Jude.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: The author of the letter was Judas, one of the brothers of Christ. Not Iscariot.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: The epistle was written about AD 62 &ndash; 70.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Judas writes a short letter urging churches to fight earnestly for the faith. He warns the church about those who sneaked into it unnoticed, and encourages the church to continue to grow in faith and love.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="book_description_730"><![CDATA[<p><strong>&bull; Book title</strong>: Revelation.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Author</strong>: Apostle John.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Date</strong>: Revelation was written at the very end of the first century, about AD 94 &ndash; 96.</p> <p><strong>&bull; Summary</strong>: Revelation is a description of the future solution to all current problems caused by sin: the Kingdom of God is physically and literally restored on earth again, the dead are resurrected, final judgments are made, a new heaven and a new earth. The main theme is God Christ in His Glory and Majesty. The truth about Christ and His final victory, which is only mentioned in other books of Scripture, becomes clear through the revelation of Jesus Christ.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="btn_testament_information_title">Testament information button</string>
    <string name="btn_testament_information_description">When you click on this button, a window with information about the Testament opens. The same button is located on the button «New Testament»</string>

    <string name="btn_notes_title">Notes</string>
    <string name="btn_notes_description">Notes store either your notes, or your notes to a specific text of the Bible.</string>

    <string name="btn_daily_verse_title">Daily Verse</string>
    <string name="btn_daily_verse_description">In Daily Verse you can randomly get Bible verses</string>

    <string name="btn_search_title">Search</string>
    <string name="btn_search_title_description">In the Search you can find the text of the Bible you need, while setting the search filter by Old or New Testament</string>

    <string name="btn_donation_title">Donate</string>
    <string name="btn_donation_description">In the Donate window you can support our ministry. We need this.</string>

    <string name="btn_settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="btn_settings_description">In Settings, you can customize the look as you like. For example, change the language or change the theme.</string>

    <string name="btn_highlighted_verses_title">Highlighted verses</string>
    <string name="btn_highlighted_verses_description">Highlighted Verses contain Bible texts that you have highlighted with a special color. This is where the highlighted texts of each individual Bible translation are stored. If you have selected a text in one translation, and then switch to another translation, then the selected texts of the previous translation will not be displayed.</string>

    <string name="btn_contact_us_title">Contact us</string>
    <string name="btn_contact_us_description">In Contact us there are buttons with transitions to one of three social networks, with the help of which you can contact us. You can ask any questions you are interested in: from technical questions to spiritual and theological questions.</string>

    <string name="book_icon_title">Book icon</string>
    <string name="book_icon_description">The icon depicts something that most closely conveys the essence of what was said in the book</string>

    <string name="btn_book_info_title">Book Information</string>
    <string name="btn_book_info_description">By clicking on this button, you will see a window with a brief description of the book. This will help you better understand the context and main idea of the book.</string>

    <string name="btn_tab_articles_title">Articles</string>
    <string name="btn_tab_articles_description">The Articles section publishes articles on biblical and theological topics</string>

    <string name="tv_privacy_policy">Privacy policy</string>
    <string name="text_ask_ads">Dear users, in the absence of any funding, the question arose about the future of our project. And we consider it our duty to know your opinion. The reason is that we have big plans for the further development of the project, but there are no necessary funds even to support it.</string>
    <string name="question_ask_ads">How would you feel about inconspicuous ads in our app?</string>
    <string name="thanks_for_vote">Thanks for your vote!</string>
</resources>